## STEPHEN GARRETT DEWYER

## software developer | user experience designer www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

Tucson, Arizona stephen.dewyer@stephengdewyer.info 248-766-8556

## software development and UX design skills

- Programming languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, Python, PHP
- JavaScript compilers, frameworks and libraries: SvelteKit, Svelte, Next.js, React, Vue.js, Express, Handlebars
- · Artificial intelligence
- Stylesheet languages: CSS 3
- Markup languages: HTML 5
- Server environments: Node
- Development environments: Visual Studio
- Database management systems: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Application programming interfaces: Representational state transfer (REST), GraphQL
- **UX design:** wire framing, prototyping, user research, user testing, information architecture, user flows, user interviews
- Digital media: Adobe Creative Cloud, photography, videography, graphic design, brand identity design, animation
- Prototyping: Figma
- eCommerce: Stripe
- Web accessibility standards: WCAG
   2 1
- Version control systems: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- Geocoding

#### awards and grants

2014 - 2016

Knight Arts Challenge Detroit matching \$20,000 grant for ∞ mile
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation
Miami, Florida

2014

Detroit Chapter June 2014 \$1,000 grant for ∞ *mile*Awesome Foundation

Boston, Massachusetts

career objective

An award-winning software developer and UX designer with over ten years of experience creating groundbreaking web programs for organizations. Experienced in working with stakeholders to produce critically-acclaimed projects. Effective at developing creative software solutions to challenging problems that help empower businesses and communities.

### professional experience

April 2021 - present

# Founding Director, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Art in Tech Services Inc

Tucson, Arizona

- Developed a client portal as a part of organization's website to help streamline client collaboration
- Record of 100% client satisfaction rate by effectively communicating throughout a client's project and meeting or exceeding project goals
- Created groundbreaking digital products that improve human experiences of technology by combining advancements in technology and art
- Successfully led the organization to achieve mission by investing in inhouse training in advanced technologies

April 2017 – present

# Founder, Full-stack Web Developer and UX Designer Public Arts Commission

Tucson, Arizona

- Developed key software programs to streamline operations that included a campaign application management system, an endorsement management system and a publicly searchable database of all the organization's endorsements
- Developing a voter networking and organizing portal
- Conducted user tests for web prototypes with Board of Directors and art experts
- Grew Board of Directors by 233% to include leading voices in the art community by delivering strong leadership
- Responsible for overall direction of the non-profit, 501(c)(4) organization

February – May 2022

# UX Design Consultant (contract) Turnberry Solutions

Minneapolis, Minnesota

- Created high-fidelity prototypes to personalize dental insurance plan shopping in the Federal Employees Dental and Vision Insurance Program (FEDVIP)
- Helped empower teams to produce great UX design for enterprise web products
- · Client: FedPoint

July 2013 – January 2017

# Web Developer and UX Designer / Co-Founding Editor $\infty$ *mile* (Infinite Mile LLC)

Detroit, Michigan

Collaborated with stakeholders to create brand and website

#### education

2009 - 2011

Master of Fine Arts (MFA) in Sculpture **Yale University School of Art** 

New Haven, Connecticut

2005 - 2008

Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) cum laude in Art History, Theory & Criticism **Maryland Institute College of Art** (MICA)

Baltimore, Maryland

#### teaching experience

2015 - 2017

Lecturer

**University of Detroit Mercy School of Architecture Digital Media Department** Detroit, Michigan

2015 - 2016

**Special Lecturer** 

2014 - 2015

Lecturer

**Oakland University Department of Art** & Art History

Rochester, Michigan

#### websites created

• 2021 – present

Art in Tech Services Inc www.artintechservices.com

• 2017 – present

**Public Arts Commission** 

www.publicartscommission.org

• 2023

**Suzanne Conti Quilts** 

https://suzannecontiquilts.vercel.app

• 2022

JoyFoodly

www.joyfoodly.com

2021 – present

web work portfolio

www.stephendewyerwebwork.com

 $\bullet$  2013 - 2017

∞ mile (Infinite Mile)

www.infinitemiledetroit.com

• 2008 – present

artist website

www.stephengdewyer.info

- Directed three editing staff and 78 contributors to publish 94 essays and interviews, 51 artist projects, 26 reviews and 27 works of fiction or poetry
- · Wrote successful grant applications
- Partnered with the University of Michigan Stamps School of Art & Design to produce two serial publications and conferences

#### technical training

2021 - 2024

# Certificates in UX Design, Software Development and Web Accessibility,

- Beginning C++ Programming From Beginner to Beyond
- Understanding TypeScript
- Machine Learning A-Z™: AI, Python & R + ChatGPT Bonus [2023]
- GraphQL by Example
- Svelte.js The Complete Guide (incl. Sapper.js)
- NodeJS The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, GraphQL, Deno)
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Web Accessibility Training Course WCAG 2.1 Compliance
- The User Researcher's guide to UX discoveries

2020 - 2021

#### Certificates in Building Web Applications, University of Michigan -Coursera

- JavaScript, ¡Query, and JSON
- Interactivity with JavaScript
- Building Database Applications in PHP
- Introduction to Structured Query Language (SQL)
- Building Web Applications in PHP

2021

#### Certificates in Database Design, University of Michigan – Coursera

- Intermediate PostgreSQL
- Database Design and Basic SQL in PostgreSQL

2020

#### Certificates in Python Programming, University of Michigan – Coursera

- Python Data Structures
- Python for Everybody

2020

#### **Certificates in UX Design, Interaction Design Foundation**

- UI Design Patterns for Successful Software
- Mobile User Experience (UX) Design
- · Become a UX Designer from Scratch
- Human-Computer Interaction

2021

#### Certificate in Leadership, University of Michigan - Coursera

Inspiring and Motivating Individuals

2/2